MOHAMMAD HASNAIN RAJAN

My core interests lie in applying my programming, Software development and AI/ML skills towards solving real world problems. Over the last 6 years while pursuing engineering, I have worked towards various projects, publications and certifications. I can learn things quickly and complete my job before deadline.

PUBLICATIONS:

+91-9867519805

Smart Home Automation Using Computer Vision And Segmented Image Processing (IEEE ICCSP 2019) https://doi.org/10.1109/ICCSP.2019.8697997.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Intern – Innovations and Research at NII Consulting Python/Django

Dec 2018-Jan 2019

- Programmed in python to generate Ad-hoc and periodic reports and deliver them via Email.
- Generate graphs relationships from logs collected by loggers in various systems.
- Also wrote python code that processes data generated by various networking tools such as Nessus and store them in Elasticsearch in a standard format

Consultant – Data Science at Ugam Solutions for the project Meaningful Insights

Jun 2018-July 2018

- Gather data from CRM and analyze it to find trends and provide insights
- Use the available data to create machine learning models for sales prediction
- Documentation and Flask API for easy access

PROJECTS:

Emotionally Intelligent Virtual AI Companion/ MYK

July 2019-Now

- An agent that can form long term relationships with the user.
- Uses graph representations for input, context and knowledgebase.

Chart Analytics

June 2019-Now

- Trained a custom CNN for classification of the charts
- Extracted Charts such as Bar Chart with their labels from FigureQa Dataset
- Using Image Processing techniques to extract numerical information from the charts **Cyberbot**

• A bot that answers Natural Language queries for a specific vulnerability given by user

- Wrote code that does transfer learning on Bert for the Question Answering
- Coded a finite state machine in python to manage states

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Jun 2016-Apr 2020

Aug 2019-Oct 2019

- MCT Rajiv Gandhi Institute of Technology, Mumbai, India
- CGPA: 9.26 (Aggregate), 9.61 (Major)
- Member, ABIT and Technical Head RES, RGIT

Udacity Computer Vision Nanodegree

Nov 2019-Dec 2019

• Image Processing, CNN, NLP, Object Tracking and Localization

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS:

- Algorithmic Toolbox by UC San Diego from Coursera.
- Image Processing by Duke University from Coursera.
- Deep Learning Specialization by Deeplearning.ai from Coursera.
- Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms using Python by NPTEL
- Machine Learning by Andrew Ng, Stanford online from Coursera.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Ranked 1st in my 2nd and 3rd year of Engineering
- Winner at Unscript 19 Hackathon. Role: Leader Of the team. Designed the system and worked on creating the Models for detection of Fake news and Question answering bot
- Smart India Hackathon 2019 Finalist. Role: Leader Of the team. Designed the system, set up Elastic stack for automatic log collection and storage and trained models for flagging types of errors generated by servers

SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: Python, SQL, JS (basic), C/C++ (basic), Java (basic)
- Platform: Linux, Windows, AWS (basic)
- Frameworks: TensorFlow, Keras, Pytorch (basic), Django, Flask
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Orator, Teamwork, Adaptability
- Languages: English, Hindi.